+91 9585625041

kevinhayesanderson@gmail.com

Chennai, India
<a href="https://kevinhayesanderson.github.io">kevinhayesanderson.github.io</a>
linkedIn.com/in/kevinhayesanderson

### **Employment Profile:**

As a Senior Software and Cloud Engineer, I have more than 6 years of experience in agile enterprise software development, cloud architecting, and developing applications using .NET and Angular frameworks. I am also proficient in Microsoft Azure Kubernetes Services, Azure App Services, Azure Functions, Azure Storage, and Azure Active Directory (AD). Additionally, I have experience in continuous integration and continuous deployment using Azure DevOps.

# **Work History:**

Ambigai Consultancy Services, Chennai, India

December 2019 - Present

**Role: Software Development Lead** 

Client 1: Schaeffler

- Developing pre- and post-processors Windows applications for finite element analysis software.
- Building core libraries for calculations in the cloud.
- Build a Native hosting suite to invoke core libraries in a native process.
- Point of reference for the team regarding fixing critical performance issues and brainstorming design.

### **Client 2: GOLDBECK GmbH**

• Developing Plugins for the Tekla Structures application

Tech Stack: Azure Functions, Azure Service Bus, Azure Storage, DevOps & Functional Programming.

### Tata Consultancy Services, Chennai, India

January 2017 - December 2019

Project 1: Cigna HealthCare

Role: .Net Developer

- Migrated legacy VB.NET application to ASP.NET MVC application.
- Developed and maintained backend services.
- Improved performance of batch processing background service.

Project 2: H&M

**Role: Full Stack Developer** 

- Developed Web APIs for domain services to support microservice architecture.
- Built a test automation suite using Selenium from scratch.
- Developed and maintained web applications built using the ASP.NET MVC framework and Angular.

Tech Stack: Angular, NET Core, ASP.NET, CQRS, Oracle Db & RabbitMQ.

### **Education:**

**Bachelor of Technology in Mechanical Engineering (8.1/10)**, Sastra University, Thanjavur.

2012 - 2016

XII (93.41/100), RSK HR. SEC. School, Tiruchirappalli.

2010 - 2011

## **Skills:**

Web (Front-end)	Web (Back-end)	Windows	Languages	Others
Angular	NET Core, ASP.NET	WPF, WinForms	C#, F#, JavaScript,	Selenium, Git, SQL
			Typescript, Python	Server

## **Certifications:**

Microsoft Certified: Azure Developer Associate, Acquired in October 2023. Credential link.

Cloud Developer using Microsoft Azure, Acquired in July 2023. Credential link.

IBM Full Stack Cloud Developer, Acquired in March 2022. Credential link.

Microsoft Certified: Azure Al Fundamentals, Acquired in April 2022. Credential link.

Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals, Acquired in March 2022. Credential link.

Microsoft Certified: Security, Compliance, and Identity Fundamentals, Acquired in February 2022. Credential link.

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals, Acquired in January 2021. Credential link.

Microsoft Technology Associate for Software Development Fundamentals, Acquired in December 2016. link. Code: nSE6-XVNa